

## CORNEA IONUŢ

## PHP Developer

### CONTACT

cornea.ionut.ci@gmail.com

+40771692996

https://www.portofolio.icornea.ro/

## **EDUCATION**

Information Technology Degree (Bachelor)

University of ORADEA 2014-2018

Baptist High school "Emanuel"

Oradea 2010-2014

## **GOOD KNOWLEDGE**

Low Code/ No Code (Bubble & Bolt)

Cloud (AWS)

Gen Al

### SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Teamwork

Organized & self discipline

## **ABOUT ME**

My motto - "Be better than yesterday in everything you do."

Passionate PHP developer with 3+ years of experience building, maintaining, optimizing robust applications.

I believe that it is important to bring value where you are.

Committed to continuous learning and excellence in development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## PHP Developer CONCENTRIX - Cluj, ROMANIA



- I single-handedly managed a project after completing my training, delivering new implementations on time while communicating directly with the client.
- Maintained scalable Drupal apps, handling backend logic (PHP, Drupal, JavaScript).
- Debugged and resolved critical application errors.
- Writing and testing the piece of code needed for the implementation of a new feature on the existing project.

## Technical Support Engineer April 2019 - April 2021 IKOULA (Hosting Provider) - Reims, FRANCE

- By creating small pieces of JavaScript scripts, I increased the efficiency of the support team's workflow.
- Main role in maintaining 40 different servers with over 12,000 clients.
   The daily activities were, troubleshooting CMS platforms (Wordpress, Magento,
   Prestashop), migrating Databases and web files, configuring mailing services.
- I was responsible in training the new comers and showing them different procedures.
   Also, I was supervising them for few days.

# Web Developer (Internship) January 2019 - March 2019 Monstock (Startup) - Bezannes, FRANCE

- Worked with the UX / UI design team to improve the layout of the website, increasing the conversion rates.
- Implementation of new functionalities for the website

## **LANGUAGES**



ROMANIAN (Native)



**ENGLISH** (Advanced)



FRENCH (Good)

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

## Database Design and Programming with SQL

- ORACLE -

Year of completion: 2016

#### Responsive Web Design

- freeCodeCamp -

Year of completion: 2020

#### React Front to Back

- UDEMY -

Year of completion: 2020

#### PHP Certification

- UDEMY -

Year of completion: 2022

#### PHP OOP Certification

- UDEMY -

Year of completion: 2024

\*can be verified on my LinkedIn

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- PHP (Laravel/ Drupal/ Wordpress)
- RESTful APIs, Unit Testing
- MYSQL, MongoDB
- Bootstrap, Tailwind

- Git / Github / GitLab
- CI/CD pipelines
- Figma / Canva / Affinity Designer

### **MY PROJECTS**

#### CMS Platform (HTML/ CSS/ JavaScript/ PHP)

 CMS Platform built with the aim of deepening my knowledge in PHP language. CRUD concept, Login system and security against MYSQL injections are all available in this project.

Pvisit project -> https://github.com/JohnCornea/cms-blog

#### Gallery (PHP OOP)

 MVC Application built in PHP OOP concept.
 CRUD concept, Static methods, Design Patterns, using PDO for secure Database connections and working with Composer.

Ø Visit project → https://github.com/JohnCornea/gallery

#### Github Profile Finder (React / Redux / Github API)

Application where you can search and find the Github profile
of any developer. The API allows detailed view of the profile
of ex. (number of repositories, number of followers, etc.)

Ø Visit project → https://githubfinder1016.netlify.app/

### REFERENCES

#### Reference 1

Position: Web Developer Company: MONSTOCK

+33784949497

guillaume.blanc@monstock.net

#### Reference 2

Position: Tech Support Company: IKOULA

+33635564771

★ tthomaszewski@ikoula.com